YouTube
what was the question we stopped with
after the first class
[Music]
yeah what are you gonna
do the higher beings want to couch in a
luxury apartment
you know
by the way I think it's going to be fun
to do shopping bags and stuff
like emanate us uh Dillard's department
store or something
for the humans right
okay
what did the Buddhists want and what
does your teacher want
chipped in
chippington
Samantha badra what's that
yeah this is this
when he's making offerings to a Buddha
he doesn't offer one rose
he fills the sky
with roses and that's an old
popular
offering meditation for Buddhas okay
okay when you're offering a flower to a
Buddha
cover the sky with with red flowers and
often that okay it's called Samantha
butter so he says chippy tin chimney's
offering chin means the clown okay
poor day
but
this is the cool part he says uh
imagine that the function of those
offerings is to increase
okay it's
you are supplying your llama with
resources
their mission
somebody from Vietnam offered me some
Red Envelope this morning you know it
already went to
editing some books okay so uh
so when you make an offering to the
Buddha
and the teacher
you're thinking I offer you resources
for your work
okay and that's what they really need
when you're talking about
offerings to a teacher
and what they really need is resources
they need they need money
not for themselves for their mission
they need uh hard work
they need people's time
and I I gotta say for example for ACI
we have these amazing translators and
staff
a large stock
keeps it going
and and it's an international huge
International stuff there's these two
weird Chinese people
pay like a hundred thousand a year
for
a hundred translators
to translate everything into Chinese
we should give him a hand
[Applause]
so uh
when you're when you're talking when
you're thinking about gifts to a teacher
they need two things they need support
for their
they need support to help people
and they need uh say
sitting
lifetime you know offer them lifetime
okay
I also offer them a few more months or a
few more years
that's that's the offering that's the
tongue tone
I've told you when you get to a llama or
a teacher
and offer them life more they need ours
if they don't have hours the the
fundraising doesn't help okay
so they need hours and they need they
need support
and they need uh
they need hard work from people
you know
lots of people ask me do you have a job
for me guess what
I'm like
I just look at them I say is this person
going to work hard or do I need to
babysit them
to be honest it comes from my corporate
base
I'm like
okay I'll take you you're a hard worker
I know you work your ass off
that's a help to babysit people it's not
a help that just takes time you know
you know so self running
hard workers who
build a stupa on their own without any
help at all from Casey Michael
we should give Cinema
[Applause]
there's someone up there enjoying it
right now it's fun for me to watch
people enjoy me
anyway congratulations on that beautiful
stupa
you saw yesterday
it's very very beautiful
and it's a
it's amazing
made from our own Stone here
which is really cool
all right uh
Gates now he's always he finished so for
dessert
uh do one day of the Realms depressing
meditation trying to
build luxury apartments in the hell
rooms
and then for dessert towards the
Thursday afternoon
okay
uh do some offerings to Buddhas instead
of like emanate us
creme brulee
or or
as red envelopes
or as lifetime like more life hours okay
and everything beautiful
that they can use
all right
uh
then we're gonna do a little more we
have some time let's use it uh it's a
juice and by the way I repeat that uh
after this class
uh general
account isn't
we'll be closing the retrieve boundaries
okay
that means silence
silence means
oh for the online
anybody want to give a definition of
Silence
no talking that's good
that's a funny thing okay
I talked twice in my three years I
remember
one
I was sitting with Christy
early in the retreat we were having
breakfast outside and this huge red
snake
came up behind her like this
like right behind her and I was like
move
uh
the other one we got now we got in an
argument I think and it it broke out of
Silence into words
okay now all right
gun
a little longitude
he says when you're giving away guitar
when you're giving away Gator what gets
her
we had it a long time ago like like 10
minutes ago
you're coming bank account you you can
call it your seed account
okay you come exceed account
don't choke here means it's cool
chill do it
it means it's okay okay you want to give
away your seeds fine
give them to people means go ahead
and
and you can do it for too soon
too soon
past present and future
no limitation
okay good karma you did 10 years ago
Good Karma you're doing today by being
in the class
Karma you're planning to do in the next
two days of
silence
uh he said fine
the seeds you can give away the three
times
[Music]
but when you're talking about your body
and your possessions
he says uh you can give this life's body
and possessions
or or your future lives body and
possessions but not
not Dippa not your past life's body and
possession I I don't know about that
maybe when you give it it's a present
memory
something like that
but
he says if you're talking about the
seeds you collected last year you can
offer those
to the hell round beings for example
but
uh I don't know last year's car
or the car it's a game the car you had
when you were 16. you don't want to
offer that anyway right
uh
so he says you can't do that I
I think that's debatable okay
don't wake up Nam
Ed
[Music]
uh he says as I mentioned before
don't wake up means when you're doing
the tongue part of
Tomlin
you're supposed to
think about what people need
and what they don't have enough of and
then you're supposed to use La Champa my
tree okay you're supposed to use love
give it to them
and then he says
hold that feeling of love
that you feel when you're doing the dumb
part of thong
and
and use that exact same feeling when you
get to lojo
hold that feeling got it
got it so the feeling the good feeling
you get when you're giving away stuff to
people mentally
hold it
keep that feeling
be able to bring it back up because
you're gonna need it when we get the
logo okay watch let's load Joe means
practice what's low
it's not
mind training like doing the
multiplication tables and stuff
okay that's also my dream okay
all right good
you know two time you saw a chicken
now uh we got five minutes
let's cram in
the thing you're gonna do Thursday
evening
for dessert dessert
my wife criticizes me
for having dessert dessert she says
dessert's okay but a second dessert
I'm like I don't know
okay
it's nice for you guys to know I have a
boss
who tells me what to do they like Gemma
cool with you jump
this is another quotation for from the
seven part
and he says make a mantra
for doing your tongue
and it can be personalized
it can be personalized okay make your
own mantra for in the next two days
you guys are responsible
to make your own mantra
for when you're doing construction in
the hell realms
stuff like that
I want a manta
from so we know you can create a mantra
for example from your llama's name
um
fill in the name and then say who
did
okay
you can make a it's called a name
and to me that's the one I did for three
years
I didn't do
the
omomom that word
and I still do it when I walk around
here I do that one uh
but he says
in the ancient tradition of thong Lan I
want a mantra that you Mumble while
you're doing
or that you can not when you're in deep
meditation okay okay but like if you're
walking around diamond mountain
to get some exercise watching carefully
for
snakes never walking Jack
barefoot which is foolish in a place
with snakes because guessing Michael
will have the fundraise for the hospital
bill
and I don't want to
uh so you know we need a mantra for your
timeline and and he says use your own
imagination
use your own
yourself a mantra
and he gives an example okay it's kind
of corny in my opinion
okay uh
samjian cookie dummy
okay that's the one from the 12th
century
I think it's corny
I think you can make something more
slick
says May the
suffering of all living beings ripen on
me instead
land
may all my happiness
talk to them
they have all my happiness
I don't like it me suffering you happy
something like that
how about me happy you happy
means something you can mutter under
your breath while you're washing dishes
and you're walking around
you know
uh just something you can uh repeat to
yourself quietly secretly
something that means something to you
some little thing to remind you of
Tomlin okay
so that's your other assignment I'm
gonna test you on Friday in front of my
boss so you better do good okay I want
some sexy
sexy self-monthrous
okay for uh
for Tomlin for your Tongan practice and
make make it yourself it's legal
the there's a rule for mantra making and
it's legal Daniel has a final question
again
yeah make your own mantra
make your own mantra
what's your Mantra gonna be for two days
not not when you're deep in meditation
okay that becomes a disturbance but like
when you're eating cooking
cleaning Marie what's her name
and condo and stuff like condo
condos in the hill room okay
all right
okay with